David Preciado

3109068978 • Phoenix, AZ • almostvenice@gmail.com • github.com/almostvenice

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

David is a self-starter business owner and highly motivated software engineer with strong problem solving skills. Proven experience and skill in creating custom business solutions using numerous Java and Javascript Frameworks, including Spring and React. Brings a hunger for learning and leverages his skills and knowledge to grow as a software developer, problem solver, and team member. As a graduate of the FastTrack Java Developer program he has displayed strong work ethics including adaptability and reliability which make him a valuable addition to any team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Java, Javascript, Python, React, React Native, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, SQL, Spring, Spring

Boot, JDBC, Jackson, JPA, JQuery, Node, Webpack, Babel, Maven, NPM

Software: Eclipse, VS Code, IntelliJ, Git, Github, Bash, Cmder, PGAdmin

Databases: PostgreSQL

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Cook Systems - Memphis, TN

07/2021 - Present

FastTrack Developer

Twitter API

- Collaborated with a team to create a RESTful API while utilizing Java Frameworks
- Finished project ahead of schedule via organizing project tasks and delivering daily reports
- Tested and maintained the API by leveraging exceptional analytical, troubleshooting and problem solving skills.
- Created a maintainable codebase through writing clean and concise code that was scalable and efficient

Environment: Java, Spring, JPA, Jackson, Maven, JDBC, PostgreSQL, PGAdmin, IntelliJ, Git, Github, Bash, Windows

Business Owner - Phoenix, AZ

12/2021 - Present

Self-employed

Created a process to automate management of multiple Air Quality Monitor networks running on the Algorand Blockchain. Problem solved a multitude of complex and unique issues to maintain maximum monitor productivity. Adapted to new rules and regulations to keep the business in compliance.

Key Accomplishments:

- Reduced time spent processing daily transactions from over 30 minutes down to 10 seconds using Algorand's API and JS SDK
- Developed a self monitoring process for the sensors to improve uptime by over 40%.

Swing Driver - Phoenix, AZ

07/2019 - 12/2021

FedEx Express

- Exceeded industry standards by dynamically solving logistics issues
- Provided prompt and accurate service through coordination with customers
- Increased productivity for the processing of FedEx office returns and fraud packages via consolidation of tasks.
- Ensured station's reliability by being proficient in over 30 different routes and 6 roles, including clerical work.

Team Lead - Fargo, ND 04/2016 - 12/2016

T-Ray Construction

• Maintained an effective workflow through rapid identification and resolution of onsite issues and communication with nearby tenants

- Increased company productivity by providing training and on-boarding services for over 10 employees
- Sustained high company output via managing prompt deployment of materials, machines and personnel to different locations at various stages of development
- Minimized injuries by actively critiquing employee lifting and operating mechanics

EDUCATION

Self-Learn Python and Excel - Phoenix, AZ 01/2022 - 02/2022

Improved my business' revenue by creating custom solutions which empowered me with more knowledge

Nucamp HTML, CSS and Javascript Course - Phoenix, AZ 02/2022 - 03/2022

Created a foundation in Web Development and acquired the skills to advance to more challenging subjects

Nucamp Full-Stack + Mobile Dev Course - Phoenix, AZ 04/2022 - 09/2022

Maximizing reusable, maintainable and scalable code through MERN stack technologies

Cook Systems FastTrack Java Program - Phoenix, AZ 07/2022 - 09/2022

Concentrating on Spring and React while collaborating with a team to create a RESTful API